<todo>
<todoitem priority="H" difficulty="2" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Pass around partially created postlist as an auto_ptr, for exception safety.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="H" difficulty="3" owner="" area="General / API" release="">

Put Om into its own namespace, to ensure lack of symbol conflicts.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="H" difficulty="5" owner="C" area="API" release="">

Write bindings for other languages (Java, C, perl, python, etc.). [In
progress, apart from C].

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="H" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Performance" release="">

Write (speed) performance test suite.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="General" release="1.0">

Check behaviour when positionlists are empty, particularly in quartz.
Test what happens if:  a positionlist is requested for a term which exists
but has no positions.  A positionlist is request for a term which does
not exist at all.  A document is inserted with a positionlist, then modified
so that there is no positionlist, and then the positionlist is requested.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="General" release="1.0">

Make sure that all methods and classes in the API have documentation
comments.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="General" release="1.0">

Check for zero byte cleanness wherever strings are used.  There are a lot
of c_str()s in the code...

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="Indexer" release="1.0">

Check that the interface used by OmDocument isn't causing great
inefficiency (vis, problems reported by Andy of large document adds taking
a great deal of time).  add_posting should be replaced by something which
takes a chunk of documents, perhaps?

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="Indexer" release="1.0">

Make OmRegexFilterNode class send unmatched items to a different output.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="Iterators" release="">

Write tests for copying term and postlist iterators.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="DA/DB" release="1.0">

Rename keys to attributes.  (OmKey -&gt; OmAttrib / OmAttribute / OmAttr ?)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="DA/DB" release="1.0">

Add get_all_terms DB databases.  Needs extra code in dbread.[ch].

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="1" owner="" area="OmQuery" release="0.9">

Add query operator to filter on weight / percentage weight.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="General" release="1.0">

Allow setting of the document length in OmDocument.  (Currently defined to
be the sum of the wdfs).

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="OmQuery" release="0.9">

Rework OmQuery interface.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="General" release="">

Make all errors return a context if appropriate.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="API" release="1.0">

"Percentage" scores - should be made more useful: a document which is indexed
by all terms should probably have a score of 100%, for example.  May need to
store the fraction of terms in the query which index the document in order to
do this: but what happens with boolean filter terms (particularly boolean not
filters)?

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Porting" release="1.0">

Produce NT version of OM.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="API" release="">

Implement methods to iterate through all the documents in the database.
Possibly via a special term which indexes all documents.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Quartz" release="1.0">

Implement deletion and updating of documents.  Test.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="API" release="">

Test that optimisations are not causing wrong results to be returned.  Have a
large dataset, and a query which returns at least 20 hits.  Perform queries
with all possible combinations of first item and mset size, and check that the
returned results are consistent.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Write tests to check that setting the parameters used in the BM25 and
traditional weighting schemes works.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Exceptions" release="">

Make exceptions threadsafe: see
http://metalab.unc.edu/pub/Linux/docs/faqs/SMP-FAQ GCC (and EGCS) need
existence of exceptions to be protected by a mutex - will need to cope with
exception being copied.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Implement collapse keys for duplicate removal - which only fire if the
two documents have the same weight.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Exceptions" release="">

Make net/omerr_string.c include om/omerrortypes.h, and use its own
#defines to process this file appropriately, so that all error types can
be dealt with.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Check that negative term weights don't mess up matcher's optimisations - if
they do we need to either disallow negative term weights, or fix/disable the
optimisations for the case of negative term weights.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Documentation" release="">

Patch doxygen, so that todo items in the body of methods get displayed.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Test performance when nth_element is run more or less frequently, to see
what is best.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="General" release="">

Check that it is safe for an exception to be thrown and caught within a
destructor, when that destructor is being called due to an exception
unwinding the stack.  eg, a database is destroyed due to an exception,
database's destructor calls internal_end_session() which throws an exception
(which is caught and handled by the destructor): is this safe - two
exceptions exist simultaneously.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Exceptions" release="">

Make exceptions work with shared libs on solaris / find an alternative. (gcc
=&gt; DISABLE_SHARED on Solaris)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="Options" release="">

Use OmSettings for specifying what debugging info to output

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Documentation" release="1.0">

Ensure that API documentation covers entirety of API.  Then rewrite it for
clarity.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Documentation" release="">

Document backend API (database, postlist, termlist, document, etc) in same
way as enquire API.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Bindings" release="">

Ensure that (Java in particular) bindings throw correct exception types.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Allow negative relevance judgements.  Will need to check that this doesn't
cause assumptions to be violated. (eg, unsigned integers going negative.)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="Stemming" release="">

Make a separate package to contain stemming algorithm stuff (docs, code,
stemtest)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Databases" release="">

Change all internal references to net/network backend to remote backend (in
step with external naming)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="5" owner="" area="DA backend" release="">

Autodetect heavy-duty vs flimsy (3 byte vs 2 byte)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Treat FILTER and AND as equivalent from the point of view of building
optimal AND trees.  Also add a variant on FilterPostList where the left
branch is boolean and the right probabilistic.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="4" owner="R" area="Matcher" release="1.0">

max_or_terms should probably work in a more local way.  Should be a new
query operator rather than a hack on OM_MOP_OR.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Threads" release="">

Make ./configure --enable-mutex-errcheck compile on more systems: need
configure check for pthread_mutexattr_settype()

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Quartz" release="">

Clean up interaction of AllTermsIterator for quartz with QuartzPostList.
Need QuartzPostListTermsIterator class?  (But with a snappier name. ;-) )

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Quartz" release="">

Make quartz database autoflush when enough changes have been performed based
on the memory used up as a proportion of that available, rather than simply
when a count of changes is reached.  Remove hardcoded count of 1000 changes.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="" area="API" release="">

Databases should return postlists and termlists as AutoPtrs, rather than
pointers.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="" area="API" release="">

Allow custom weighting functions.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="" area="API" release="">

Provide fake term which indexes all documents.  This would be used for a
real "NOT" operator, and also for allowing searches to be scored based on
location (would give weight from location for this term, with a custom
weighting scheme).

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="" area="API" release="">

Provide explicit support for range searches.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

max_or_terms should never select groups of terms which don't match any
documents.  (Currently, will exclude those for which termfreq_max() is 0,
but this may still result in a bad choice)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

max_or_terms should probably reduce the querysize by the number of terms
removed - hard to do because max_or_terms necessarily happens after some
term weights have been calculated...

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Purify" release="">

Write autoconf macro to turn on purify support. Submit to
http://peti.cys.de/autoconf-archive/

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Documentation" release="1.0">

Add notes about catching exceptions throughout userman, particularly in
examples (eg, search engine example)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="c" area="Backends" release="">

Use thread locks around inmemory methods

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="2" owner="" area="Website" release="">

Put PS/PDF documentation on website.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="5" owner="c" area="General" release="">

Audit for exception safety.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="4" owner="R" area="Positional" release="">

Test get_position_list() methods on databases.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="API" release="">

Re-implement OmBatchEnquire, and add back into the system.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Weighting" release="">

Allow for a non-zero minimum value for the ndl (normalised doc len).

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Positional" release="">

Passage retrieval.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="L" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Clustering algorithms.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="V" difficulty="5" owner="" area="General" release="">

Improve performance using SIMD instructions

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="V" difficulty="4" owner="" area="General" release="">

Make backends / weighting schemes / indexer modules register themselves
automatically.  At runtime / linktime? (ie, replace current conditional
compilation scheme)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="V" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Backends" release="">

Split database definition files into database/postlist/termlist files.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="V" difficulty="4" owner="" area="General" release="">

A couple of classes get copied a lot - look into doing copy-on-write for
them.  Notably ExpandBits and term names (currently strings so this happens,
but may change)

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="D" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Exceptions" release="">

Add error handlers to (at least) OmDatabase.  Implement more carefully in
MergePostlist.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="D" difficulty="3" owner="" area="Decision functors" release="">

Return a sensible value for OmMSet::matches_lower_bound when a decision
functor is present: perhaps this should be matches_considered, but then again
perhaps not.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="D" difficulty="3" owner="" area="API" release="">

Do allow boolean subqueries in OmQuery constructors, where
it makes sense (or note in documentation to use FILTER).

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="D" difficulty="5" owner="" area="Matcher" release="">

Boolean filters result in collection statistics being for the wrong set of
documents (should be appropriate subset).  Hard (impossible?) to implement
efficiently.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="M" difficulty="2" owner="" area="Distributed" release="1.0">

Make timeout absolute, rather than cumulative, when fetching multiple documents
from database: if two nodes fail, the total timeout should still be that
specified, not twice it.

</todoitem>
<todoitem priority="H" difficulty="2" owner="" area="Distributed" release="1.0">

Make OmMSet::fetch() fetch only items which havn't already been requested.
Also, just call request document for those items, and only call collect
document when actually desiring to access the data.  (Collect document _must_
be called in same order as request document though.)

</todoitem>
</todo>
